EN				JP	Number	JobNo	Overview(Old)
					(BE)

Precision			精密	1B	3	Keeps your arrows from flying off mark when you loose them whilst in motion #LV UP: Further decreases deviation.
Fireproof			防炎	3E	4	Decreases damage received from Fire attribute attacks #LV UP: Further decreases damage.
Counter				合昇	52	5	Increases Force Gauge when a blocked attack matches the element enchanted to your rod #LV UP: Further increases Force Gauge.
Adhesion			悠握	6F	2	Makes it harder for an enemy to throwyou off whilst you're clinging to it #LV UP: Further decreases likelihood of stagger.
Break Formation			倒陣	7E	6	"Increases the Blow Power of Magic Trap,allowing it to break enemy posture more easily #LV UP: Further increases Blow Power."
Recovery Burst			甦活	9F	8	"While in a near-death state, increases health recovery speed when affected by healing spells #LV UP: Further increases recovery speed."
First Strike			初突	B5	7	"When your Revenge Gauge is consumed,your Savage Lash and Indomitable Lash's intialquake has increased Blow Power #LV UP: Further increases Blow Power."
Lively Romp			舞活	CD	9	Recovers your stamina upon a successful Alchem Fuga #LV UP: Further increases stamina recovery.
Soft Touch			柔触	E7		Reduces damage from hazards such as spikesor stalactites #LV UP: Further reduces damage taken.
Extended Spirit			延霊	1-95	A	Slows the drain of the Spirit Gauge in normal mode #LV UP: Further slows the drain.
Extended Glyph			延印	1-D3	B	Slows the drain of Magick Glyph #LV UP: Further decreases the drain.
Counter				受倒	4	1	Increases the Knockout Power of perfect blocks #LV UP: Further increases Knockout Power.
Delayed Explosion		遅爆	22	3	Extends the time period that explosive arrows will linger before exploding #LV UP: Further extends time.
Reduce Burn			減炎	43	4	"Decreases the rate at which you receive the debilitation ""Catching Fire"" whenstruck by Fire attribute attacks #LV UP: Further increases resistance."
Adamance			壮防	55	5	Decreases the Stamina consumed when you block attacks with your shield #LV UP: Further decreases Stamina consumption.
Reverse Stance			制倒	74	2	Decreases likelihood of being staggered while rolling #LV UP: Further decreases likelihood.
Comfortable Levitate		楽揚	8E	6	Decreases Stamina consumption while using Levitate #LV UP: Further decreases Stamina consumption.
Verge of Death			死線	A6	8	"While in a near-death state, increases health and decreases the likelihood of maximum recoverable health lowering #LV UP: Further increases health recovery."
Ferocity			壮堪	BF	7	"When your health is above a certain amount,increases your poise and makes you harder to stagger #LV UP: Further increases poise."
Vicious Vision			奪視	CE	9	Increases threat generation when attacking #LV UP: Further increases threat generation.
Extended Springs		延泉	E8		Increases the effect length of mineralspring baths #LV UP: Further increases effect length.
Foraging Heal			採癒	1-9F	A	Health recovers when collecting items(Item drops from enemies and treasure chests are excluded) #LV UP: Recovered amount increases.
Fierce Flight			烈翔	1-D9	B	Ruin Blade accumulates element faster when enchanted #LV UP: Increases status effect accumulation.
Fitness				剛腕	F	1	Decreases the Stamina consumed whenyou grapple-hold opponents #LV UP: Further decreases Stamina consumption.
Hidden Potential		底力	2A	3	Increases your Blow Power when you stand at death's door #LV UP: Further increases Blow Power.
Assist Defense			防助	39	4	Provides allies with increased Defense after picking them up from incapacitation #LV UP: Further increases duration of the effect.
Prominence			異彩	4F	5	Increases the rate at which Attract generates enemy attention #LV UP: Further increases attention.
Leap Grip			躍握	6D	2	"Decreases Stamina consumed by the ""Shake"" action #LV UP: Further decreases Stamina consumption."
Equanimity			至極	89	6	Amplifies your Magick when you stand atdeath's door #LV UP: Further increases Magick.
Aid Extension			延助	9A	8	Extends the flight distance of True Aid Arrow #LV UP: Further extends flight distance.
Mangle				斬刻	B4	7	Extends the just timing window for Savage Lash and Indomitable Lash #LV UP: Further extends window.
Majestic Might			絶威	D6	9	Increases stamina recovery when you stand at death's door #LV UP: Further increases stamina recovery.
Enhanced Throw			強投	EC		Increases the damage of thrown items #LV UP: Further increases damage.
Pleasant Touch			触快	1-A2	A	After using the Touch actionto assist a party member out of a status abnormality.Their maximum stamina is increased for a certain period of time #LV UP: Increases duration further.
Protective Glyph		護印	1-DE	B	Slows the drain of Magick Glyph when you are damaged or staggered #LV UP: Further reduces the drain.
Counter Extension		受拡	5	1	Extends the attack range of perfect block counters #LV UP: Extends the range further.
Damping				制動	1A	3	Decreases recoil after firing your bow #LV UP: Decreases recoil further.
Spirit Overflow			漲魂	34	4	Decreases the attention of enemies while using Field Shift #LV UP: Decreases attention further.
Supercharge			過給	51	5	Increases the effect durationof Force Enchantment #LV UP: Increases duration further.
Longline			延縄	65	2	Extends the flying distance of the Seeker Rope #LV UP: Extends the distance further.
Continued Chant			続詠	81	6	"Allows use of Back Move while charging magic.The charge will continue, but you will suffer a penalty to the chant gauge #LV UP: Decreases penalty to thechant gauge further."
Fire Affinity			炎襲	A7	8	Increases chance to cause burning when attacking enemies with fire element attacks #LV UP: Further increases burning chance.
Forced Endure			迫堪	C0	7	Increases poise and reduces your chance to be staggered when you stand at death's door #LV UP: Further increases poise.
Instant Recovery		即復	DA	9	Decreases the time in which you are defenseless after your stamina is depleted #LV UP: Further decreases defenseless duration.
Gathering			探採	E4		Increases the range at which gathering points will display on the map. 
Evasive Shadow			避影	1-96	A	Increases swirling speed of Scar Move #LV UP: Further increases speed.
Strong Shot			強弾	1-D5	B	Increases damage and blow power of Ruin Shot #LV UP: Further increases damage and blow power.
Agile Motion			敏動	1	1	"Decreases the charge time of Guard Break,allowing you to swing the sword more quickly #LV UP: Decreases charge time further."
Concentration			集中	1E	3	Extends the time period for active reload #LV UP: Extends time further.
Iceproof			防氷	3F	4	Decreases damage received from Ice attribute attacks #LV UP: Decreases damage further.
Vibrant Defense			揺抑	59	5	Decreases damage received when staggering after your guard is broken #LV UP: Decreases damage further.
Assisted High Jump		高舞	7B	2	Increases jump height when assisted by another person #LV UP: Increases jump height further.
Fire Attack			攻炎	82	6	Increases damage dealt with the Fire attribute #LV UP: Increases damage further.
Ice Affinity			氷襲	A8	8	Increases chance to cause freezing when attacking enemies with ice element attacks #LV UP: Further increases freezing chance.
Overflowing Hatred		湧恨	B1	7	Your revenge gauge fills more easily when you stand at death's door #LV UP: Gauge fills even faster.
Prolonged Lure			延囮	CB	9	Extends the duration of the catalyst left by Alchem Fuga #LV UP: Further extends duration.
Efficacy			薬効	EB		Increases the effect of healing items #LV UP: Further increases effect.
Threatened Spirit		迫霊	1-94	A	Increases amount of spirit gained from attacks when you stand at death's door #LV UP: Further increases gained amount.
Perilous Absorption		危吸	1-D4	B	Increases the amount of magick absorbed from sword attacks when you stand at death's door #LV UP: Further increases magickal energy absoprtion.
Exhilaration			本領	9	1	Provides a surge in strength when you stand at death's door #LV UP: Increases Strength further.
Sturdy Form			逞姿	24	3	Increases Stamina recovery speed while your bow is ready to fire #LV UP: Increases Stamina recovery further.
Reduce Freeze			減氷	44	4	"Decreases the rate at which you receive the debilitation ""Frozen Solid"" when struck by Ice attribute attacks #LV UP: Increases resistance further."
Sanctuary			開悟	5D	5	Improves your Defense and Magick Defense when you stand at death's door #LV UP: Increases Defense and Magick Defense further.
Giant Safeguard			巨護	7C	2	Decrease damage received from Giant enemies #LV UP: Decreases damage further.
Ice Attack			攻氷	83	6	Increases damage dealt with the Ice attribute #LV UP: Increases damage further.
Life Energizer			勢命	A0	8	Slows the rate at which your maximum recoverable health decreases from attacks #LV UP: Further slows rate of decrease.
Undying Force			迫当	B8	7	"Increases your stun power when you stand atdeath's door, allowing you to more easily stun enemies #LV UP: Further inreases stun power."
Calming Vision			乖視	D0	9	Decreases your threat generation evenwhen attacking enemies #LV UP: Further decreases threat generation.
Effect Extension		効延	ED		Increases the effect duration of effects granted by items #LV UP: Further extends duration.
Foraging Spirit			採霊	1-9B	A	Gain a portion of spirit when collecting items(Item drops from enemies and treasure chests are excluded) #LV UP: Further increases gained amount.
Active Supression		活鎮	1-E3	B	Increases exhaust attack #LV UP: Further increases exhaust attack.
Egression			速離	10	1	Facilitates easier escapes from enemy grapple-holds #LV UP: Increases escape ease further.
Perfect Reload			匠填	21	3	"Extends the time window for a master reload, making it easier to perform #LV UP: Extends time window further."
Assist Magick			魔助	3A	4	Provides allies with increased Magick Defense after picking them up from incapacitation #LV UP: Increases duration of the effect.
Perky				溌剌	63	5	Increases your health after leaving White Dragon Temple for a period of time #LV UP: Increases health further.
Tremor-proof			耐揺	6A	2	Decreases Stamina consumption when resisting an enemy's attempt to shake you off #LV UP: Decreases Stamina consumption further.
Thunder Attack			攻雷	84	6	Increases damage dealt with the Thunder attribute #LV UP: Increases damage further.
Life Spark			煌命	A1	8	Slows the rate at which your maximum recoverable health decreases from damage when you standat death's door #LV UP: Further slows rate of decrease.
Forced Attack			迫攻	BC	7	"Increases your chance attack power when you standat death's door, allowing you to down enraged enemies more easily #LV UP: Further increases chance attack power."
Soul Stealer			魂吸	DB	9	Greatly recovers your stamina when you land the finishing blow on an enemy #LV UP: Further increases stamina recovered.
New Attack			新攻	F0		Increases your magical and physical power during a new moon #LV UP: Further increases physical/magical power.
Protective Touch		触防	1-A1	A	After using the Touch action to assist a party member out of a status abnormality.Their Physical and Magick Defense is increased for a period of time #LV UP: Increases effect duration.
Imperative Supression		迫鎮	1-E5	B	Increases exhaust attack when you stand at death's door #LV UP: Further increases exhaust attack.
Advantageous Feeling		受得	6	1	"Relax your blocking, allowing recovery of Stamina upon performing perfect blocks #LV UP: Increases Stamina recovery further."
Ogre Proficiency		鬼狙	32	3	Increases damage dealt to Ogre enemies #LV UP: Increases damage further.
Thunderproof			防雷	40	4	Decreases damage received from Thunder attribute attacks #LV UP: Decreases damage further.
Frugal Defense			長守	54	5	Allows some Force Gauge to remain after your gauge is consumed #LV UP: Increases the amount further.
Rope Reversal			縄倒	66	2	"Increases the Blow Power of your Seeker Rope,increasing the likelihood it will break enemy posture #LV UP: Increases Blow Power further."
Demon Proficiency		魔狙	92	6	Increases damage dealt to Demon enemies #LV UP: Increases damage further.
Thunder Affinity		雷襲	A9	8	Increases chance to cause shock when attacking enemies with thunder element attacks #LV UP: Further increases shock chance.
Malice				熟怨	B2	7	"At max revenge gauge, your defense increases and you do not stagger from enemy attacks #LV UP: Further increases defense and poise."
Well-Practiced			速錬	CC	9	Decreases the time required to prepare your Elixir #LV UP: Further decreases preparation time.
New Defense			新防	F1		Increases your physical and magic defense during a new moon #LV UP: Further increases defenses.
Critical			臨堅	1-9D	A	When a boost is activated Physical and Magick Defense are increased for a period of time #LV UP: Increases effect duration.
Increased Absorption		加吸	1-D8	B	Increases the amount of magick absorbed by sword attacks #LV UP: Further increases the absorbed amount.
Soft Proficiency		軟狙	19	1	Increases damage dealt to Soft enemies #LV UP: Increases damage further.
Winged Proficiency		翼狙	30	3	Increases damage dealt to Winged enemies #LV UP: Increases damage further.
Reduce Shock			減雷	45	4	"Decreases the rate at which you receive the debilitation ""Shock"" when struck by Thunder attribute attacks #LV UP: Increases resistance further."
Prescience			見極	57	5	"Allows you to more easily perform perfect blocks, just as foes strike #LV UP: Extends the perfect blocktime window further."
Giant Proficiency		巨狙	7D	2	Increases damage dealt to Giant enemies #LV UP: Increases damage further.
Cursed Proficiency		呪狙	94	6	Increases damage dealt to Cursed enemies #LV UP: Increases damage further.
Spirit Proficiency		霊狙	AD	8	Increases the damage you deal towards spirit-type enemies #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.
Inner Strength			精当	B9	7	"Increases your stun power when your stamina is above a certain amount, making enemies easier to stun #LV UP: Further increases stun power."
Apparentness			顕在	D3	9	Reduces loss of enemy attention from over time #LV UP: Further reduces loss of enemy attention.
Rain Attack			雨攻	F4		Increases your physical and magic power during rainy weather #LV UP: Further increases physical/magic power.
Active				臨活	1-98	A	"When a boost is activated, Stamina will recover #LV UP: Increases amount of stamina recovered."
Fortunes of War			武運	1-DF	B	Has a chance to not consume stamina when you use custom skills #LV UP: Further increases the chance.
Demihuman Proficiency		亜狙	17	1	Increases damage dealt to Demihuman enemies #LV UP: Increases damage further.
Ogre Safeguard			鬼護	31	3	Decreases damage received from Ogre enemies #LV UP: Decreases damage further.
Skeleton Proficiency		骨狙	4B	4	Increases damage dealt to Skeleton enemies #LV UP: Increases damage further.
Denial				抗意	56	5	Decreases damage received from overblocking #LV UP: Decreases damage further.
Jump Proficiency		力跳	78	2	Decreases likelihood of being staggered when damaged in the air #LV UP: Decreases likelihood further.
Demon Safeguard			魔護	91	6	Decrease damage received from Demon enemies #LV UP: Decreases damage further.
Construct Proficiency		造狙	AF	8	Increases the damage you deal towards magickal constructed enemies #LV UP: Further increases damage.
Beast Proficiency		獣狙	C8	7	Increases the damage you deal towards beast-type enemies #LV UP: Further increases damage.
Alchemized Safeguard		錬護	DE	9	Decrease damage received from alchemized enemies #LV UP: Decreases damage further.
Rain Defense			雨防	F5		Increases your phyiscal and magic defense during rainy weather #LV UP: Further increases defenses.
Attack Touch			触攻	1-A0	A	After using the Touch action to assist a party member out of a status abnormality.Their Physical and Magick Attack is increased for a period of time #LV UP: Increases effect duration.
Magickal Charge			魔充	1-D2	B	Increases Strength and Magick when number magickal stack is more than 2 #LV UP: Further increases Strength and Magick.
Soft Safeguard			軟護	18	1	Decreases damage received from Soft enemies #LV UP: Decreases damage further.
Winged Safeguard		翼護	2F	3	Decreases damage received from Winged enemies #LV UP: Decreases damage further.
Undead Proficiency		腐狙	49	4	Increases damage dealt to Undead enemies #LV UP: Increases damage further.
Solid				堅牢	58	5	Increases the guard power of the shield making it easier to withstand stronger attacks #LV UP: Further increases guard power.
Light Recoil			軽跳	79	2	Decreases Stamina consumption while in the air #LV UP: Decreases Stamina consumption further.
Cursed Safeguard		呪護	93	6	Decrease damage received from Cursed enemies #LV UP: Decreases damage further.
Quick Healing			快癒	A5	8	"Increases your recovery power, and slows the rateat which your maximum recoverable health decreases #LV UP: Further increases recovery power."
Fighting Spirit			精攻	BD	7	"Increases your chance attack power when your stamina is above a certain amount, making enraged enemies easier to down #LV UP: Further increases chance attack power."
Flourishing Healing		華療	CF	9	Increases the threat generation of healing actions #LV UP: Further increases threat generation.
Expert Excavator		巧掘	E5		Decreases the chance of gathering items breaking on use #LV UP: Further decreases break chance.
Avoidance			避活	1-99	A	Recover stamina when avoiding enemy attacks with Scar Move #LV UP: Increases recovered Stamina further.
Courageous Supression		勇鎮	1-E4	B	Increases exhaust attack when your health is above certain level #LV UP: Further increases exhaust attack.
Demihuman Safeguard		亜護	16	1	Decreases damage received from Demihuman enemies #LV UP: Decreases damage further.
Skilled Reload			巧填	1F	3	Recover Stamina when performing a master reload #LV UP: Increases recovered Stamina further.
Skeleton Safeguard		骨護	4A	4	Decreases damage received from Skeleton enemies #LV UP: Decreases damage further.
Trickle				貪吸	4D	5	Increases the rate at which you gain Force Gauge #LV UP: Increases gain further.
Sky Hammer			空撃	75	2	Increases damage of aerial attacks #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.
Spirit Chant			精唱	7F	6	Restores Stamina upon successful spell inputs #LV UP: Increases Stamina restored further.
Spirit Safeguard		霊護	AC	8	Decrease damage received from spirit-type enemies #LV UP: Decreases damage further.
Resolute			精堪	C1	7	"Increases your poise when you stamina is above acertain amount, making you harder to stagger #LV UP: Further increases poise."
Encouraged			迫技	D8	9	Decreases the amount of stamina consumed bycustom skills when you stand at death's door #LV UP: Further decreases stamina consumed.
Flow				流断	E6		Lowers the movement speed penalty when in water or poison pools #LV UP: Further decreases movement penalty.
Evasive Spirit			避霊	1-9E	A	Gain a portion of spirit when avoiding enemy attacks with Scar Move #LV UP: Increase gained amount further.
Vigorous Supression		精鎮	1-E6	B	Increases exhaust attack when your stamina is above certain level #LV UP: Further increases exhaust attack.
Brave Effort			壮腕	A	1	Increases Strength when your Stamina is above a certain amount #LV UP: Increases Strength further.
Arrow Increase			充矢	1D	3	Increases the number of arrows that canbe loaded into the quiver at a time #LV UP: Increases arrow count further.
Undead Safeguard		腐護	48	4	Decreases damage received from Undead enemies #LV UP: Decreases damage further.
Violent Release			烈放	50	5	Increases the rate at which Force Burst applies elemental debilitations #LV UP: Increases debilitation rate further.
High Jump			高跳	68	2	Increases the jump height of your Double Jump #LV UP: Increases jump height further.
Graceful Chant			麗詠	80	6	"Decreases the difficulty of doing Chanting inputs,making it easier to increase the magic's power #LV UP: Decreases difficulty further."
Construct Safeguard		造護	AE	8	Decrease damage received from magickal constructed enemies #LV UP: Decreases damage further.
Bestial Instinct		獣護	C7	7	Decrease damage received from beast-type enemies #LV UP: Decreases damage further.
Alchemized Proficiency		錬狙	DF	9	Increases the damage you deal towards alchemized enemies #LV UP: Further increases damage.
Featherfoot			羽踏	E9		Decreases fall damage taken when falling from high places #LV UP: Decreases damage further.
Extended Healing		長癒	1-9A	A	Extends the duration of Aid/Aid More #LV UP: Increases effect duration further.
Augmented Magick		増魔	1-D6	B	Increases magickal attack after pure magick invocation for a period of time #LV UP: Further increases duration.
Dire Gouge			狂刺	2	1	Increases attack speed when using Gouge #LV UP: Increases attack speed further.
Menacing Form			威姿	23	3	Decreases chance to be staggered when aiming withthe bow #LV UP: Further decreases stagger chance.
Relaxed Cure			緩療	33	4	Decreases Stamina consumption while channeling Heal Aura and Holy Aura #LV UP: Decreases Stamina consumption further.
Dedication			専心	5F	5	Increases resistance to Lowered Magic Defense #LV UP: Further increases resistance.
Adhesion			粘着	70	2	Reduces stamina drain from enemies trying to shake you off #LV UP: Further decreases stamina drain.
Dark Attack			攻闇	86	6	Increases the damage dealt by dark attribute attacks #LV UP: Further increases damage.
Heal Extension			延療	9C	8	Increases the duration of the spheres left by magic arrows with healing or recovery properties #LV UP: Further increases sphere duration.
Aggression			超恨	B0	7	Increases revenge gauge gains from counterattacks #LV UP: Further increases revenge gauge gains.
Alchemical Invasion		侵錬	CA	9	Increases the effectiveness of your chosen status when activating Elixir #LV UP: Further increases status effectiveness.
Moonlight Assault		月攻	F2		Increases your physical and magic power during full moons #LV UP: Further increases physical/magic power.
Attack Rescue			救攻	1-B1	A	When rescuing an incapacitated party member both you and the member will receive increased Physical Attackpower for a period of time #LV UP: Increases effect duration further.
Altered Magick			転魔	1-D7	B	Increases physical attack after pure magick invocation for a period of time #LV UP: Further increases duration.
Heavy Shield			重盾	C	1	Enemies are staggered more easily when attacking with the shield #LV UP: Further increases blow power.
Heart Shot			芯撃	27	3	Increases the stagger power of your arrows when standing at the perfect range #LV UP: Further increases stagger power.
Patience			我慢	3D	4	Decreases damage taken while out of stamina #LV UP: Further decreases damage taken.
Perseverance			堅忍	60	5	Increases resistance to Physical Defense Down #LV UP: Further increases resistance.
Flip Resistance			翻防	77	2	Decreases the damage you take while airborne #LV UP: Further decreases damage taken.
Calmness			泰然	8A	6	Increases your magic power when your stamina is above a certain amount #LV UP: Further increases magic power.
Holy Affinity			聖襲	AA	8	Increases the chance of causing Holy Drain when attacking with holy element attacks #LV UP: Further increases Holy Drain chance.
Weighted			重当	B6	7	"Increases your stun power, making it easier to stun enemies #LV UP: Further stun power."
Discreet Healing		慎療	D1	9	Decreases the threat generation of healing actions #LV UP: Further decreases threat generation.
Moonlight Defense		月防	F3		Increases physical and magic defense during full moons #LV UP: Further increases defenses.
Resistance			耐附	1-A6	A	"When receiving an enchantment,damage received by an attack of the same element will be decreased #LV UP: Further decrease damage taken."
Heavy Foot			厚足	1-E2	B	Lower damage and status effect accumulation from terrains such as poison and magma #LV UP: Further decreases damage and status effect accumulation.
Obstinacy			意地	11	1	Decreases damage taken when grabbed by enemies #LV UP: Further decreases damage taken.
Decisive Shot			射極	2D	3	"Increases your damage dealt towards parts weak against missile attacks, but reduces your damage to parts strong against them #LV UP: Further increases damage."
Holyproof			防聖	41	4	Decreases damage taken from holy attacks #LV UP: Further decreases damage taken.
Holy Body			聖体	61	5	Increases resistance to Curse #LV UP: Further increases resistance.
Sound Landing			健着	7A	2	Decreases the chance of staggering from runningjumps #LV UP: Further decreases stagger chance.
Extended Levitate		延浮	8F	6	Increases the duration of levitation #LV UP: Further increases duration.
Dark Affinity			闇襲	AB	8	Increases the chance of causing Darkness when attacking with dark element attacks #LV UP: Further increases Darkness chance.
Violence			烈当	B7	7	"Increases your stun power when your health is above a certain amount, making it easier tostun enemies #LV UP: Further increases stun power."
Diminishing			薄在	D4	9	Increases loss of enemy attention from time elapsing #LV UP: Further increases loss of enemy attention.
Treasure Eye			宝眼	E2		Increases the range in which treasure will appear on your map. 
Immovable			不動	1-A7	A	Increases endurance while reviving a party member #LV UP: Further increases amount of endurance.
Source Luck			源運	1-E0	B	Has a chance to not consume Force/Revenge/Magick Gauge #LV UP: Further increases the chance.
Nullifying Defense		無衝	13	1	Increases the invulnerability period when you quick-recover from a knockdown #LV UP: Further increases invulnerability period.
Enhancement			充実	29	3	"Increases your stagger power when your health is above a certain amount, making it easier to stagger enemies #LV UP: Further increases stagger power."
Darkproof			防闇	42	4	Decreases the damage you take from dark element magic #LV UP: Further decreases damage taken.
Fired Up			気鋭	5C	5	Increases your physical/magic defense when your health is above a certain amount #LV UP: Further increases defenses.
Arm-Strength			腕力	69	2	Decreases stamina consumption while grabbing onto enemies #LV UP: Further decreases stamina consumption.
Human Safeguard			人護	95	6	Decreases damage taken from humanoid-type enemies #LV UP: Further decreases damage taken.
United Energy			一勢	97	8	Increases the rate at which your magic power increase from targeting multiple enemies with Magic Eye #LV UP: Further increases magic power increase rate.
Brave Attack			勇攻	BB	7	"Increases your chance attack power when your health is above a certain amount, increasing your chance to down enraged enemies #LV UP: Further increases chance attack power."
Tender Touch			優撫	D2	9	Decreases threat generation while grabbing onto enemies #LV UP: Further decreases threat generation.
Willpower			根性	E3		Allows you to survive an attack with 1 HP remaining when struck by an attack that would kill you while below a certain amount of health.Effect resets on logging out or resting at an inn #LV UP: Increases health threshold for effect to trigger.
Refreshing Rescue		爽快	1-A8	A	Party members you revive will have increased maximum stamina for a period of time #LV UP: Increases effect duration further.
War-Ready Safeguard		戦護	1-E9	B	Reduces damage taken from War-Ready enemies #LV UP: Further reduce damage taken.
Combat Momentum			闘勢	8	1	Increases your physical strength when your health is above a certain amount #LV UP: Further increases physical strength.
Aggression Arrow		侵矢	20	3	Increases the effectiveness of status effect-inducing arrows #LV UP: Further increases status effectiveness.
Attack Aid			攻援	37	4	Temporarily increases the physical attack power of allies you revive #LV UP: Further increases effect duration.
Absorption			積吸	4C	5	Increases the attack power drain of Force Guard/Force Gain #LV UP: Further increases attack power drain.
Spin Avoid			避旋	67	2	Increases the speed of your dodge roll #LV UP: Further increases speed.
Holy Attack			攻聖	85	6	Increases the damage you deal with holy element attacks #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.
Quick Arrow			迅矢	99	8	Increases the flight speed of your magic arrows #LV UP: Further increases flight speed.
Heavy Attack			重攻	BA	7	"Increases your chance attack power, making it easier to down enraged enemies #LV UP: Further increases chance attack power."
Cordial Climb			快登	D9	9	Increases stamina recovery while grabbing onto enemies #LV UP: Further increases stamina recovery.
Rakshasa			羅刹	EE		Increases your maximum health at night #LV UP: Further increases maximum health.
Infected Safeguard		侵護	1-AB	A	Decreases damage taken from Infected enemies #LV UP: Further decreases damage taken.
Bombardment			砲撃	1-E1	B	Increases damage and blow force when using artillery #LV UP: Further increases damage and blow force.
Steadfast Stand			硬台	12	1	Reduces damage taken and makes you harder to stagger while in the stance for an assisted jump #LV UP: Further reduces damage taken.
Hardy				強壮	2B	3	"Increases your stagger power while above acertain amount of stamina, making enemieseasier to stagger #LV UP: Further increases stagger power."
Magick Aid			魔援	38	4	Temporarily increases the magic attack power of allies you revive #LV UP: Further increases effect duration.
Divided Strength		岐精	53	5	Recovers your stamina after executing Shield Sequence #LV UP: Further increases stamina recovered.
Flying Evasion			跳避	71	2	Increases the distance of evasion actions #LV UP: Further increases distance.
Magick Boost			魔増	88	6	Increases magic power when your health is above a certain amount #LV UP: Further increases magic power.
Mending				修復	A3	8	"Recovers health while you stand at death's door,but taking damage will temporarily cancel the effect #LV UP: Further increases health recovered."
Hard Body			硬身	C3	7	Reduces damage taken while charging attacks #LV UP: Further reduces damage taken.
Heroic Spirit			英気	DC	9	Increases your maximum stamina #LV UP: Further increases maximum stamina.
Yasha				夜叉	EF		Increases your maximum stamina at night #LV UP: Further increases maximum stamina.
Sprout Sealing			封芽	1-9C	A	Prolongs the duration that infected sprouts are sealed #LV UP: Increases duration of sealing further.
Armor Crusher			甲砕	1-E8	B	Increases damage and blow force against armor parts of War-Ready enemies #LV UP: Further increases damage and blow force.
Crush Receive			受崩	3	1	Increases the stagger power of your shield counters #LV UP: Further increases stagger power.
Reload Force			力填	1C	3	Reduces damage taken while reloading arrows #LV UP: Further reduces damage taken.
Reduce Holy Drain		減聖	46	4	Reduces the chance of being afflicted with Holy Drain from holy element attacks #LV UP: Further reduces affliction chance.
Instant Recovery		即直	5A	5	Reduces time of vulnerability when staggered while blocking or hitting an enemy #LV UP: Further reduces vulnerability time.
Enduring Grip			耐握	6E	2	Reduces damage taken while grabbing onto an enemy #LV UP: Further reduces damage taken.
Persistent Cast			魔抗	8C	6	Reduces chance of being staggered by attacks while casting spells #LV UP: Further reduces chance of being staggered.
Heal Thyself			自療	9D	8	Increases the amount healed by your Healing Dress #LV UP: Further healing power.
Ambition			覇気	C4	7	Reduces chance of being staggered by attacks while charging attacks #LV UP: Further reduces chance of being staggered.
Challenger			挑錬	C9	9	Increases the rate at which you alchemize enemies with your attacks #LV UP: Further increases alchemize rate.
Safe Landing			安着	EA		Increases the height from which you can safely fall #LV UP: Further increases safe fall height.
Reduced Corruption		減侵	1-A9	A	Increases resistance to the corruption status #LV UP: Further increases resistance.
War-Ready Proficiency		戦狙	1-EA	B	Increases damage dealt to War-Ready enemies #LV UP: Further increases damage.
Toppling Shield			倒盾	D	1	Increases the stun power of your shield attacks #LV UP: Further increases stun power.
Shadow Attack			陰討	2E	3	Increases the damage you deal towards enemies not in combat stance #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.
Reduce Blind			減闇	47	4	Reduces chance of being afflicted by Darknessfrom dark element attacks #LV UP: Further reduces chance status affliction.
Great Vigor			精強	5E	5	Increases your physical and magic defense when your stamina is above a certain amount #LV UP: Further increases defenses.
Calm Evasion			鎮逸	73	2	Reduces damage taken while performing evasive actions #LV UP: Further reduces damage taken.
Ignore Intimidation		朗威	90	6	Increases resistance to MagicAttack Down #LV UP: Further increases resistance.
Deathly Devour			忌吸	A4	8	Recovers health when you deal the finishing blow to an enemy #LV UP: Further increases health recovered.
Heavy Steps			重歩	C5	7	You are unaffected by wind pressure. 
Vigorous Vitality		盛精	D5	9	Increases stamina recovery rate #LV UP: Further increases stamina recovery rate.
男心〈246〉			男心	F6		男性へのプレゼント譲渡時に好感度がより上昇する 
Infected Destroyer		侵壊	1-AA	A	Increases damage to infected enemy's growths #LV UP: Further increases damage.
Complement Chant		節補	1-DD	B	"When using support magick, a tiny portion of magick gauge remains #LV UP: Further increases the remaining portion."
Fortitude			不屈	15	1	Increases resistance to PhysicalAttack Down #LV UP: Further increases resistance.
Pleasant Attack			快撃	26	3	Increases attack power when standing at the perfect range #LV UP: Further increases attack power.
Compassion			慈覧	35	4	Reduces threat generation from deploying HealAura #LV UP: Further reduces threat generation.
Invigorated			活性	62	5	Increases maximum health #LV UP: Further increases maximum health.
Destructive Fall		烈墜	76	2	Increases the damage of drop attacks performed from high places #LV UP: Further increases damage.
Magick Energy			魔精	8D	6	Recovers stamina while casting spells #LV UP: Further increases stamina recovery.
Lengthy Assistance		拡助	98	8	Increases the just timing window of tracking targets a second time with Magic Eye tofire a stronger magic arrow #LV UP: Further increases timing window.
Unyielding Posture		高堪	BE	7	"Increases poise, making you harder to stagger #LV UP: Further increases poise."
Dragonkin Safeguard		竜護	E0	9	Reduces damage taken from dragon-type enemies #LV UP: Further reduces damage taken.
女心〈247〉			女心	F7		女性へのプレゼント譲渡時に好感度がより上昇する 
Extension			延臨	1-97	A	Decreases the rate at which the spirit gauge drops during boost mode #LV UP: Further decreases reduction rate.
Strong Shield			強盾	B	1	Increases damage caused by shield attacks #LV UP: Further increases damage.
Attack Expansion		拡撃	25	3	Increases the range in which arrows will deal the greatest amount of damage #LV UP: Further increases range.
Divine Protection		加護	3C	4	Reduces damage taken #LV UP: Further reduces damage taken.
Robust				壮健	5B	5	Increases physical and magic defense #LV UP: Further increases defenses.
Furious Grip			握烈	6B	2	Increases damage dealt while grabbing onto enemies #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.
Twin Magick			魔双	87	6	Increases magic power #LV UP: Further increases magic power.
Self Feedback			自回	A2	8	Recovers health when damaging enemies #LV UP: Further increases health recovered.
Prolonged Hatred		延恨	B3	7	Slows rate at which your revenge gauge depletes #LV UP: Further slows depletion.
Relaxedness			快動	D7	9	Reduces stamina consumed by custom skills #LV UP: Further reduces stamina consumption.
Resist Poison			抗毒	F8		Increases resistance to Poison #LV UP: Further increases resistance.
Synergy				合附	1-A4	A	"When receiving an enchantment,the damage dealt to an enemy currently affected by the same element's affliction increases #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt."
Magickal Chant			節魔	1-DB	B	"When using pure magick, a tiny portion of magick gauge remains #LV UP: Further increases the remaining portion."
Onslaught			猛攻	7	1	Increases physical power #LV UP: Further increases physical power.
Herculean Strength		剛力	28	3	"Increases blow power, making it easier to stagger enemies #LV UP: Further increases blow power."
Long Exposure			長露	36	4	Increases the duration of secret cores #LV UP: Further increses duration.
Great Absorption		猛吸	4E	5	Recovers stamina on a successful Force Gain #LV UP: Further increases stamina recovered.
Quakemaker			与震	6C	2	Increases the rate at which shaking an enraged enemy drains their stamina #LV UP: Further increases stamina drain.
Courageous Cast			胆唱	8B	6	Reduces damage taken while casting spells #LV UP: Further reduces damage taken.
Persistent Arrow		執矢	9B	8	Increases the tracking power on magic arrows and allows them to more accurately follow targets #LV UP: Further increases tracking power.
Full Bodied			渾身	C2	7	Increases the stagger power of your charged attacks #LV UP: Further increases stagger power.
Polished Poise			快錬	DD	9	Recovers your stamina when using a fully alchemized Elixir #LV UP: Further increases stamina recovered.
Anti-slow			抗遅	F9		Increases resistance to Slow #LV UP: Further increases resistance.
Attribution			属附	1-A5	A	"When receiving an enchantment,the chance to apply an elemental affliction is increased #LV UP: Further increases affliction chance."
Anti-Reduction			抗滅	1-E7	B	Status effect accumulation on yourself decreases when you are attacking enemies #LV UP: Further decreases status effect accumulation.
Overpower			圧伏	E	1	Increases the duration of holding enemies #LV UP: Further increases duration.
Tough Skin			硬皮	2C	3	Reduces the damage you take from missile attacks #LV UP: Further reduces chance of being staggered.
Encouragement			激励	3B	4	Temporarily increases the maximum health of allies you revive #LV UP: Further increases effect duration.
Eased Blade			緩刃	64	5	Reduces damage taken from slash attacks #LV UP: Further reduces damage taken.
Superior Evasion		優避	72	2	Increases the invincibility time for evasion skills #LV UP: Further increases invincibility time.
Humanoid Proficiency		人狙	96	6	Increases the damage you deal toward humanoid-type enemies #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.
Quick Healing			急活	9E	8	Increases recovery speed when affected by healing magic #LV UP: Further increases recovery speed.
Deft Footing			穿歩	C6	7	You are unaffected by tremors. 
Dragonkin Proficiency		竜狙	E1	9	Increases damage dealt toward dragon-type enemies #LV UP: Further increases damage done.
Anti-sleep			抗眠	FA		Increases resistance to Sleep #LV UP: Further increases resistance.
Infected Proficiency		侵狙	1-AC	A	Increases damage dealt toward infected enemies #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.
Soaring Sword			翔剣	1-DA	B	"Increases amount of magic gauge consumed by Ruin Blade,greatly increasing its damage #LV UP: Further increases damage."
Resilience			強靭	14	1	Reduces damage taken from striking attacks #LV UP: Further reduces damage taken.
Anti-stun			抗絶	FB		Increases resistance to Stun #LV UP: Further increases resistance.
Archery: Slayer			弓射 倒	1-34	3	Increases the damage of your basic arrow attacks #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases stagger power.
Healing: Chant			癒気 詠	1-40	4	"Increases the healing done by Heal Aura, Greater Heal Aura, and Ride Heal Aura #LV UP: Further increases resistance.LV5~6: Increases cast speed."
Shieldbash: Slayer		盾打 倒	1-4C	5	Increases the damage of Shield Blow #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases stagger power.
Carve: Slayer			連斬 倒	1-58	2	Increases the damage of Carve #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases stagger power.
Magick Bolt: Slayer		魔弾 倒	1-64	6	Increases the damage of Magick Bolt #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases stagger power.
Seeker: Slayer			闘矢 倒	1-70	8	Increases the damage of Seeker #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases stagger power.
Hack: Slayer			破斬 倒	1-7C	7	Increases the damage of Hack #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases stagger power.
Alchemic Strike: Slayer		錬打 倒	1-88	9	Increases the damage of Alchem #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases stagger power.
Rushing Spear: Slayer		槍突 倒	1-AD	A	Increases damage of Thrust #LV UP: Increases damage further.LV5~6: Increases blow power.
Quadruple Slash: Slayer		四撃 倒	1-F3	B	Increases damage of Quadruple Slash #LV UP: Increases damage further.LV5~6: Increases blow power.
Anti-drench			抗水	FC		Increases resistance to Drench #LV UP: Further increases resistance.
Onslaught: Slayer		連撃 倒	1-28	1	Increases the damage of Onslaught #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases stagger power.
Exploding Arrow: Fury		爆矢 烈	1-35	3	Increases the damage of Explosive Arrows #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases status effect rate.
Blast Bits: Slayer		破球 倒	1-41	4	Increases the damage of Blast Bit #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases stagger power.
Weaklight: Fury			属照 烈	1-4D	5	Increases the damage of Weaklight #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases status effect rate.
Scarlet Kisses: Slayer		裂斬 倒	1-59	2	Increases the damage of Scarlet Kisses/Hundred Kisses #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases stagger power.
Magick Trap: Crush		魔罠 砕	1-65	6	Increases the damage of Magick Trap #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases chance attack and exhaust attack power.
Aid Arrow: Chant		助矢 詠	1-71	8	Increases the healing of True Aid Arrow #LV UP: Further increases healing.LV5~6: Increases cast speed.
Inverse Slash: Crusher		魔倒 砕	1-7D	7	Increases the damage of Inverse Slash #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases chance attack and exhaust attack power.
Alchemic Evade: Slayer		錬避 倒	1-89	9	Increases the damage of Alchem Fuga #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases stagger power.
Rising Spear: Slayer		槍昇 倒	1-AE	A	Increases damage of Air Thrust #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases blow power.
Arc Slash: Slayer		弧撃 倒	1-F4	B	Increases damage of Arc Slash #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases blow power.
Anti-oil			抗油	FD		Increases resistance to Oil Doused #LV UP: Further increases resistance.
Demolishing Strike: Slayer	斬崩 倒	1-29	1	Increases the damage of Guard Break/Strong GuardBreak #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases stagger power.
Arrowhead Strike: Fury		矢斬 烈	1-37	3	Increases the damage of Arrowhead Strike #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases status effect rate.
Saint Aura: Slayer		聖気 倒	1-43	4	"Increases the damage of Saint Aura, Greater Saint Aura, and Ride Saint Aura #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases stagger power."
Force Burst: Crush		攻爆 砕	1-50	5	Increases the damage of Force Burst #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases chance attack and exhaust attack power.
Scarlet Slashes: Crush		乱斬 砕	1-5C	2	Increases the damage of Scarlet Slashes/Hundred Slashes #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases chance attack and exhaust attack power.
Magick Cracker: Slayer		魔破 倒	1-6B	6	Increases the damage of Magick Cracker #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases stagger power.
Forward Kick: Slayer		一蹴 倒	1-73	8	Increases the damage of Forward Kick #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases stagger power.
Savage Lash: Eradicate		魔斬 絶	1-80	7	Increases the damage ofSavage Lash/Indomitable Lash #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases stun power.
Elixer: Slayer			錬爆 倒	1-8C	9	Increases the damage of Elixir #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases stagger power.
Crushing Spear: Slayer		槍墜 倒	1-B0	A	Increases damage of Fall Thrust #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases blow power.
Sky Slash: Slayer		空叉 倒	1-F6	B	Increases damage of Sky Slash #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases blow power.
Anti-seal			抗封	FE		Increases resistance to Skill Stifling #LV UP: Further increases resistance.
Gouge: Eradicate		抉突 絶	1-2B	1	Increases the damage of Gouge #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases stun power.
Rigid Stance			硬構	1-36	3	Increases physical and magic defense while aiming your bow #LV UP: Further increases defenses.
Assist Boost			扶魔	1-42	4	Decreases damage from magic attacks temporarily after reviving a party member #LV UP: Further extends effect duration.
Protected Mend			護治	1-4E	5	Slows rate at which maximum recoverable health decreases from attacks while guarding #LV UP: Further slows rate of decrease.
Enduring Sprint			走耐	1-5A	2	Increases physical and magic defense and makes you harder to stagger while dashing/dash jumping #LV UP: Further increases defense/stagger resist.
Enduring Levitation		硬浮	1-66	6	Increases physical and magic defense while Levitating #LV UP: Further increases defenses.
Steady Advance			快進	1-72	8	Increases maximum stamina temporarily after leaving the White Dragon Temple #LV UP: Further increases maximum stamina.
Brandish			快閃	1-7E	7	Recovers stamina when just timing a chargeattack. Reduces stamina consumption for justtimed custom skills #LV UP: Further increases stamina recovered.
Enduring Vision			硬視	1-8A	9	Increases physical and magic defense when attracting enemy attention as a Tank #LV UP: Further increases defenses.
Enhanced Vitality		活発	1-B2	A	Increases maximum health #LV UP: Further increases maximum health.
Falling Slash: Slayer		昇墜 倒	1-F5	B	Increases damage of Fall Slash #LV UP: Increases damage further.LV5~6: Increases blow power.
Anti-subdue			抗軟	FF		Increases resistance to Subdued #LV UP: Further increases resistance.
Crushing Blow			崩攻	1-2A	1	Increases physical attack temporarily after breaking enemy guard #LV UP: Further increases effect duration.
Keensight Shot: Slayer		静射 倒	1-38	3	Increases damage of Keensight shots #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases blow power.
Shockwave: Slayer		衝破 倒	1-44	4	Increases damage dealt by the shockwave created when cancelling Field Shift #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases blow power.
Shield Counter: Savage		盾序 烈	1-4F	5	Increases the damage of Shield Counter #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases chance of inflicting status abnormalities.
Roundhouse Kick: Slayer		回蹴 倒	1-5B	2	Increases the damage of Roundhouse Kick #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases blow power.
Magick Cracker: Smasher		魔破 砕	1-68	6	Increases the damage of Magick Cracker #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases stagger power.
Invigorating Arrows: Duration	奮矢 据	1-74	8	Increased Stamina recovery amounton targets hit by or around recovery field #LV UP: Further increases recovered amount.LV5~6: Increases effect duration.
Devastate: Slayer		広斬 倒	1-7F	7	Increases the damage of Devastate #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases blow power.
Alchemical Radius: Slayer	錬衝 倒	1-8B	9	Increases the damage of Alchemical Radius #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases blow power.
Sweeping Spear: Slayer		槍円 倒	1-AF	A	Increases the damage of Thrust More #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases blow power.
Ordinary Attack			常撃	1-F1	B	Increases damage of all core skills #LV UP: Further increases damage.
Anti-petrify			抗石	1-00		Increases resistance to Petrify #LV UP: Further increases resistance.
Dire Onslaught: Slayer		強連 倒	1-2C	1	Increases the damage of Dire Onslaught #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases blow power.
Rescue Assistance		救耐	1-39	3	When you revive a party member they will have increased Physical Defense for a period of time #LV UP: Increases effect duration further.
Stagnation			滅吸	1-45	4	"When landing the finishing blow on an enemy,your Stamina recovers #LV UP: Further increase recovered Stamina."
Attention			集視	1-51	5	Increases threat generation when attacking #LV UP: Further increases threat generation.
Deep Aggression			深攻	1-5D	2	"Increases your chance attack power, making iteasier to down enraged enemies #LV UP: Further increases chance attack power."
Collapsing Strength		倒力	1-69	6	"Increases blow power, making it easier to stagger enemies #LV UP: Further increases blow power."
Demon Shield			魔遮	1-75	8	Increases Magick Defense power #LV UP: Further increases Magick Defense.
Attack Cover			攻遮	1-81	7	Increases Physical Defense power #LV UP: Further increases Physical Defense.
Stubborn			頑強	1-8D	9	"Increases poise, making you harder to stagger #LV UP: Further increases poise."
Elemental Defense		防属	1-B7	A	Reduces the damage of elemental attacks(Fire/Ice/Lightning/Holy/Darkness) #LV UP: Further decreases damage received.
Respiration			偏吸	1-F8	B	"Increases Magick Glyph growth when using sword skills,but also increases Magick Glyph decay when being staggered #LV UP: Further increases growth rate."
Anti-goldify			抗金	1-01		Increases resistance to Goldify #LV UP: Further increases resistance.
Firm Shield			堅盾	1-2D	1	Increases the guard power of the shield making it easier to withstand stronger attacks #LV UP: Further increases guard power.
Archery: Crusher		弓射 砕	1-3A	3	Increases the damage of basic arrow attacks #LV UP: Further increases damage.LV5~6: Increases chance and exhaust attack.
Heal Aura: Endurer		癒気 耐	1-46	4	Increases the recovery amount of Heal Aura / Greater Heal Aura / Ride Heal Aura #LV UP: Further increases recovery amount.LV5~6: Increases endurance while aura is deployed.
Shield Blow: Crusher		盾打 砕	1-52	5	Increases the amount of damage dealt by shield blow #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases chance and exhaust attack.
Carve: Crusher			連斬 砕	1-5E	2	Increases the amount of damage dealt by Carve #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases chance and exhaust attack.
Magick Bolts: Crusher		魔弾 砕	1-67	6	Increases damage of Magick Bolts #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases chance and exhaust attack.
Seeker Arrows: Blink		闘矢 瞬	1-76	8	Increases damage of Seeker Arrows #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases the damage gained upon a successful Just Release.
Hack: Crusher			破斬 砕	1-82	7	Increases damage of Hack #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases chance and exhaust attack.
Alchemy: Crusher		錬打 砕	1-8E	9	Increases damage of Alchemy #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases chance and exhaust attack.
Rushing Spear: Destroyer	槍突 破	1-B3	A	Increases damage of Thrust #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases chance and exhaust attack.
Quadruple Slash: Absorption	四撃 吸	1-ED	B	Increases damage of Quadruple Slash #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases magickal energy absorption.
Close to Fire			親炎	1-02		Increases resistance to Fire Defense Down #LV UP: Further increases resistance.
Onslaught: Crusher		連撃 砕	1-2E	1	Increases damage of Onslaught #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases chance and exhaust attack.
Exploding Arrow: Crusher	爆矢 砕	1-3B	3	Increases damage of Exploding Arrows #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases chance and exhaust attack.
Blast Bits: Crusher		破球 砕	1-47	4	Increases damage of Blast Bits #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases chance and exhaust attack.
Weak Light: Crusher		属照 砕	1-53	5	Increases damage of Weak Light #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increase chance and exhaust attack.
Scarlet Kisses: Crusher		裂斬 砕	1-5F	2	Increases damage of Scarlet Kisses/Hundred Kisses #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increase chance and exhaust attack.
Magick Trap: Duration		魔罠 据	1-6A	6	Increases damage of Magick Trap #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases duration of Magick Trap.
Aid Arrow: Blink		助矢 瞬	1-77	8	Increases recovery amount of True Aid Arrow #LV UP: Further increases recovery amount.LV5~6: Increases recovery amount bonus gained upon a successful Just Release
Inverse Slash: Exterminator	魔倒 絶	1-83	7	Increases damage of Inverse Slash #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases stun power.
Alchemic Evade: Crusher		錬避 砕	1-8F	9	Increases damage of Alchemical Fuga #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases chance and exhaust attack.
Rising Spear: Destroyer		槍昇 破	1-B4	A	Increases damage of Air Thrust #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases chance and exhaust attack.
Arc Slash: Destroyer		弧撃 吸	1-EE	B	Increases damage of Arc Slash #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases magickal energy absorption.
Close to Ice			親氷	1-03		Increases resistance to Ice Defense Down #LV UP: Further increases resistance.
Demolishing Strike:Exterminator	斬崩 絶	1-2F	1	Increases damage of Guard Break/Strong Guard Break #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases stun power.
Arrowhead Strike: Crusher	矢斬 砕	1-3D	3	Increases the damage of Arrowhead Strike #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases chance and exhaust attack.
Holy Aura: Savage		聖気 烈	1-49	4	Increases damage of the following:Holy Aura/Greater Holy Aura/Ride Holy Aura #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases status affliction accumulation.
Force Burst: Slayer		攻爆 倒	1-56	5	Increases the damage of Force Burst #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases blow power.
Scarlet Slashes: Exterminator	乱斬 絶	1-62	2	Increases the damage of Scarlet Slashes/Hundred Slashes #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases stun power.
Magick Cracker: Singer		魔破 詠	1-6E	6	Increases the damage of Magick Cracker #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases casting speed.
Front Kick: Crusher		一蹴 砕	1-79	8	Increases the damage of Front Kick #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases chance and exhaust attack.
Savage Lash: Crusher		魔斬 砕	1-86	7	Increases the damage of SavageLash/Indomitable Lash #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases chance and exhaust attack.
Elixir: Crusher			錬爆 砕	1-92	9	Increases damage of Elixir #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases chance and exhaust attack.
Crushing Spear: Destroyer	槍墜 破	1-B6	A	Increases the damage of Fall Thrust #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases chance and exhaust attack.
Sky Slash: Absorption		空叉 吸	1-EF	B	Increases damage of Sky Slash #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases magickal energy absorption.
Close to Thunder		親雷	1-04		Increases resistance to Thunder Defense Down #LV UP: Further increases resistance.
Gouge: Crusher			抉突 砕	1-31	1	Increases the damage of Gouge #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases chance and exhaust attack. 
Augmented Spirit		増精	1-3C	3	Increases your maximum stamina #LV UP: Further increases maximum stamina.
Magickal Rush			魔猛	1-48	4	Increases magic power #LV UP: Further increases magic power.
Shield Collapse			盾崩	1-54	5	Enemies are staggered more easily when attacking with the shield #LV UP: Further increases blow power.
Stiffness			剛攻	1-60	2	Increases physical power #LV UP: Further increases physical power.
Reduction			減属	1-6C	6	Increases resistance against Burn/Freeze/Electrify/Holy Drain/Blind #LV UP: Further increases resistance.
Salvational Magick		救魔	1-78	8	Increases Magickal Attack power for aperiod of time when assisting and reviving party members #LV UP: Increases effect duration further.
Great Grasp			豪握	1-84	7	Increases damage dealt while grabbing onto enemies #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.
Sky Annihilation		空滅	1-90	9	Increases damage of aerial attacks #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.
Great Enchantment		強附	1-A3	A	Increases damage dealt to enemies when the weapon is enchanted #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.
Falling Slash: Absorption	昇墜 吸	1-F0	B	Increases damage of Falling Slash #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases magickal energy absorption.
Close to Holy			親聖	1-5		Increases resistance to Holy Defense Down #LV UP: Further increases resistance.
Hardening			硬溜	1-30	1	Reduces damage taken while charging an attack #LV UP: Further decreases damage received.
Keensight: Crusher		静射 砕	1-3E	3	Increases damage of Keensight shots #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases chance and exhaust attack.
Shockwave: Crusher		衝破 砕	1-4A	4	Increases the damage of the shockwave generated when cancelling Field Shift #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases chance and exhaust attack. 
Shield Sequence: Crusher	盾序 砕	1-55	5	Increases damage of Shield Sequence #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases chance and exhaust attack.
Roundhouse Kick: Crusher	回蹴 砕	1-61	2	Increases the damage of Roundhouse Kick #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases chance and exhaust attack.
Magick Trap: Singer		魔罠 詠	1-6D	6	Increases the damage of Magick Trap #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases casting speed.
Invigoration Arrow: Expand	奮矢 拡 1-7A	8	Increases the stamina recovery amount of Invigorating Arrow #LV UP: Further increases recovery amount.LV5~6: Expands range of effect.
Devastate: Crusher		広斬 砕	1-85	7	Increases the damage of Devastate #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases chance and exhaust attack.
Alchemical Radius: Crusher	錬衝 砕	1-91	9	Increases the damage of Alchemical Radius #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases chance and exhaust attack.
Sweeping Spear: Destroyer	槍円 破	1-B5	A	Increases the damage of Thrust More #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases chance and exhaust attack.
Rush Attack			移撃	1-F2	B	Increases the damage of skills that move you forward #LV UP: Further increases damage.
Close to Dark			親闇	1-6		Increases resistance to Dark Defense Down #LV UP: Further increases resistance.
Dire Onslaught: Crusher		強連 砕	1-32	1	Increases the damage of Dire Onslaught #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.LV5~6: Increases chance and exhaust attack.
Climax Bow			至弓	1-3F	3	Increases the damage of the triple shot arrow gainedupon a perfect reload #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.
Hard Spirit			硬気	1-4B	4	Increases Physical and Magickal Defense power while Heal Auraor Holy Aura are currently active #LV UP: Further increases Physical and Magickal Defense power.
Pleasant Sight			快視	1-57	5	Reduces stamina consumption of Attract/More Attract #LV UP: Further reduces stamina consumption.
Pleasant Roll			快転	1-63	2	Reduces stamina cost of Forward Roll #LV UP: Further reduces stamina cost.
Pleasant Drift			快漂	1-6F	6	Reduces stamina cost of Back Move #LV UP: Further reduces stamina cost.
Counter Eye			通眼	1-7B	8	The duration that secret cores revealed by Magick Eye: True Aidare exposed is greatly extended #LV UP: Further increases the duration.
Excess Grudge			残恨	1-87	7	"When using Savage Lash or Indomitable Lash,a tiny portion of the revenge gauge remains when the gauge is consumed #LV UP: Further increases remaining gaugeamount."
Defense Alchemy			守錬	1-93	9	"When detonating a maximized Elixir, Physical and Magickal Defensepower is increased for a period of time #LV UP: Increases duration of effect."
Spirit Hoard			霊蓄	1-B8	A	Increases Spirit Gauge gained from attacks #LV UP: Further increases Gauge gains.
Flow Attack			流撃	1-F7	B	Increases damage for skills that trigger based on enemy's attacks #LV UP: Further increases damage.
Control Poison			制毒	1-07		Increases recovery speed from Poison #LV UP: Further increases recovery speed.
Pleasant Thrust			快突	1-33	1	Reduces stamina cost of Gouge #LV UP: Further increases reduction amount.
Control Slow			制遅	1-8		Increases recovery speed from Slow #LV UP: Further increases recovery speed.
Control Sleep			制眠	1-9		Increases recovery speed from Sleep #LV UP: Further increases recovery speed.
Control Stun			制絶	1-A		Increases recovery speed from Stun #LV UP: Further increases recovery speed.
Quick Drying			速乾	1-B		Increases recovery speed from Drenched #LV UP: Further increases recovery speed.
Quick Clean			速清	1-C		Increases recovery speed from Oil Doused #LV UP: Further increases recovery speed.
Quick Seal			縮封	1-D		Increases recovery speed from Seal #LV UP: Further increases recovery speed.
Reduce Subdue			縮軟	1-E		Increases recovery speed from Subdued #LV UP: Further increases recovery speed.
Reduce Petrify			縮石	1-F		Increases time to full petrification when afflicted with Petrify #LV UP: Further increases time to petrification.
Reduce Goldify			縮金	1-10		Increases time to full petrification when afflicted with Goldify #LV UP: Further increases time to petrification.
Reduce Tar			縮焼	1-11		Increases recovery speed from Burning #LV UP: Further increases recovery speed.
Reduce Freeze			縮凍	1-12		Increases recovery speed from Freeze #LV UP: Further increases recovery speed.
Reduce Blind			縮霧	1-13		Increases recovery speed from Darkness #LV UP: Further increases recovery speed.
Reduce Fire			縮炎	1-14		Increases recovery speed from Fire Defense Down #LV UP: Further increases recovery speed.
Reduce Ice			縮氷	1-15		Increases recovery speed from Ice Defense Down #LV UP: Further increases recovery speed.
Reduce Thunder			縮雷	1-16		Increases recovery speed from Thunder DefenseDown #LV UP: Further increases recovery speed.
Reduce Holy			縮聖	1-17		Increases recovery speed from Holy Defense Down #LV UP: Further increases recovery speed.
Reduce Dark			縮闇	1-18		Increases recovery speed from Dark Defense Down #LV UP: Further increases recovery speed.
Reduce Physical Attack Down	縮攻	1-19		Increases recovery speed from Physical AttackDown #LV UP: Further increases recovery speed.
Reduce Defense Down		縮防	1-1A		Increases recovery speed from Physical DefenseDown #LV UP: Further increases recovery speed.
Reduce Magick Attack Down	縮念	1-1B		Increases recovery speed from Magic Attack Down #LV UP: Further increases recovery speed.
Reduce Magick Defense Down	縮衰	1-1C		Increases recovery speed from Magic Defense Down #LV UP: Further increases recovery speed.
増褒〈285〉			増褒	1-1D		平日 20:00 ～ 26:00 のあいだ、グランドミッションの戦果ポイントが増加する 
加奨〈286〉			加奨	1-1E		平日 02:00 ～ 11:00 のあいだ、敵を討伐したとき得られるゴールドが増加する 
匠誉〈287〉			匠誉	1-1F		平日 11:00 ～ 20:00 のあいだ、ワールド／ボードクエストクリアで得られるエリアポイントが増加する 
輝褒〈288〉			輝褒	1-20		休日 20:00 ～ 26:00 のあいだ、グランドミッションで得られるリムが増加する 
勝賞〈289〉			勝賞	1-21		休日 02:00 ～ 11:00 のあいだ、敵の討伐時に得られる経験値が増加する 
共得〈290〉			共得	1-22		休日 11:00 ～ 20:00 のあいだ、クランミッションで得られるクランポイントが増加する 
Music Hunter			奏狩	1-23		"Sets Battle BGM to ""Proof of a Hero""(Monster Hunter). "
Music May Cry			奏泣	1-24		"Sets Battle BGM to ""Devils Never Cry""(Devil May Cry). "
Music Fighter			奏隆	1-25		"Sets Battle BGM to ""Japan (Ryu)""(Street Fighter). "
Wily Music			奏撃	1-26		"Sets Battle BGM to ""Dr. Wily Stage 1"" (Megaman). "
Music 'n Goblins		奏魔	1-27		"Sets Battle BGM to ""Plains BGM""(Ghosts 'n Goblins). "
Companion Health		友体	1-B9		Increases maximum health of pawns in your party #LV UP: Further increases maximum health.
Companion Stamina		友活	1-BA		Increases maximum stamina of pawns in your party #LV UP: Further increases maximum stamina.
Companion Attack		友攻	1-BB		Increases physical power of pawns in your party #LV UP: Further increases physical power.
Companion Magick		友魔	1-BC		Increases magic power of pawns in your party #LV UP: Further increases magic power.
Companion Defense		友防	1-BD		Increases physical defense of pawns in your party #LV UP: Further increases physical defense.
Companion Magick Defense	友護	1-BE		Increases magic defense of pawns in your party #LV UP: Further increases magic defense.
Follow-up Attack		追討	1-BF		Increases damage dealt toward held-down enemies #LV UP: Further increases damage dealt.
Companion Healing		友癒	1-C0		Increases maximum recoverable health of pawns inyour party when an enemy is slain #LV UP: Further increases maximum recoverable health.
Heavy Steps: Light		重歩 軽	1-C1		You are unaffected by wind pressure. 
Deft Footing: Light		穿歩 軽	1-C2		You are unaffected by tremors. 
Extended Springs: Light		延泉 軽	1-C3		Increases the duration of mineral bath effects #LV UP: Further increases duration.
Gathering: Light		探採 軽	1-C4		Increases the range at which gathering points will display on the map. 
Efficacy: Light			薬効 軽	1-C5		Increases the effect of healing items #LV UP: Further increases effect.
Effect Extension: Light		効延 軽	1-C6		Increases the effect duration of effects granted by items #LV UP: Further extends duration.
Expert Excavator: Light		巧掘 軽	1-C7		Decreases the chance of gathering items breaking on use #LV UP: Further decreases break chance.
Flow: Light			流断 軽	1-C8		Lowers the movement speed penalty when in water or poison pools #LV UP: Further decreases movement penalty.
Treasure Eye: Light		宝眼 軽	1-C9		Increases the range in which treasure will appear on your map. 
Willpower: Light		根性 軽	1-CA		Allows you to survive an attack with 1 HP remaining when struck by an attack that wouldkill you while below a certain amount of health.Effect resets on logging out or resting at an inn #LV UP: Increases health threshold for effect to trigger.
Safe Landing: Light		安着 軽	1-CB		Increases the height from which you can safely fall #LV UP: Further increases safe fall height.
Ease Burden			減重	1-CC		Decreases the weight of equipped items #LV UP: Further decreases item weight.
Myrmidon			戦徒	1-CD		"Grant the effect beyond LV.6 of the following augments:Companion Health, Companion Stamina, Companion Attack,Companion Magick, Companion Defense, Companion Magick Defense.No effect when equipped on pawn. "
Inquiry				探究	1-CE		"Grants the following augments:Gathering, Treasure Eye. Grant the effect beyond LV.6 of the following augments:Extended Springs, Safe Landing, Flow, Efficacy.Gathering, Treasure Eye have no effect when equipped on pawn. "
Purge				侵滅	1-CF		"Grant the effect beyond LV.6 of the following augments:Infected Destroyer, Infected Safeguard,Reduced Corruption, Great Grasp, Hardy. "
Night Emperor			夜帝	1-D0		"Grant the effect beyond LV.6 of the following augments:Rakshasa, Yasha, Sky Annihilation,Egression, Holy Body. "
